<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://tiympc.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://tiympc.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-10-03T14:42:04-07:00</updated><id>https://tiympc.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">tiympc</title><subtitle>© 2023 | tiympc</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A PRECIOUS review of history that should never be forgotten.</title><link href="https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/10/08/title.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A PRECIOUS review of history that should never be forgotten." /><published>2023-10-08T22:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-10-08T22:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/10/08/title</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/10/08/title.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Will be released on October 8, 2023.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Will be released on October 8, 2023.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My MOST important journey to date.</title><link href="https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/10/01/title.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My MOST important journey to date." /><published>2023-10-01T22:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-10-01T22:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/10/01/title</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/10/01/title.html">&lt;p&gt;📍 San Francisco, CA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post takes this blog in a completely different direction. Enjoy the randomness, but I am not sure I’ll keep this here for much longer. This post is extremely personal and shouldn’t really be on the internet…I should figure out how to rid my name entirely from this blog to remain anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between 2016 and 2020, I gained around 40 pounds of clean muscle through a consistent exercise schedule. As a varsity sport athlete, I took what I learned in high school and built off of my momentum by maintaing an athletic physique in college. When COVID happened, I was in the best shape of my life. I was a fighting machine, bench pressing 175 and squatting 225 on normal sets, far above the normal numbers for someone weighing in at 140 pounds at 5’ 6”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some gained considerable weight as a result of COVID, I was the total opposite. Life slapped me across the face and I was too afraid to get back up. A negligence towards the gym, a dependance on stimulants like caffeine, a self-induced depression, an entire year of illness that put me in bed for 80 days of 2022 (literally 80), and a surgery to fix said illness doesn’t bode well for your physical health. I lost about 20 pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, it doesn’t matter how badly we fall. It’s about how badly we’re willing to get back up. And I’m willing to get back up and then some. I’ve already been feeling great for months now: My faith in God is at its best, and I’m ready for a comeback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of October 1st, 2023, I am weighing in at 123 pounds with a height of 5’ 8”. I am feeling motivated to improve how I look and win back that feeling of accomplishment when you know you’re the baddest motherfucker in that gym. For me, this is an intrinsic motivation that nobody can take away from me. I tend to have an animalistic obsession about certain things that I would never want any of my competitors to have. It’s a gift and a curse, but right now it has been years since I’ve felt this way about the gym, so I’ll take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I am about to do something great. My ancestors are going to watch me become the strongest man in my entire bloodline, both physically and mentally (no disrespect to my father, brothers, or any of my ancestors). God gave me a vehicle called a body, and though I couldn’t have asked for a sportier model 😎, it’s time I walk the walk. That said, my goal is to weigh in at 150 lbs by my 24th birthday, approximately 7 months away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am at the stage of my life where I am genuinely starting to feel confident in my abilities and mindset (confidence is a mindset). It took me my entire life to get to this conclusion, but these past several months &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt;, I’ve attained a certain confidence much more potent than any confidence I’ve ever felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am starting to feel like a man, and not for reasons most would assume. My brothers and sisters depend on me to lead them, despite being the second youngest of five. It is a great burden but also a great responsibility; one I am willing to take for the sake of love. There is a sense of purpose and reassurance associated with being the person that those close around you depend on. I have genuinely stopped caring about what others think of me. I no longer compare myself in unhealthy ways. I am not trying to be someone I am not. These are the reasons I am a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my journey of manhood begins, I can be one of two people. The first sits around on October 31st generating excuses left and right as to why they didn’t work towards their goal. Or, I can be the second person, who hit the gym 12 times, started eating seriously, and says to himself: “I gained 4 pounds this month, let me do 4 fucking more in November.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TIYMPC&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">📍 San Francisco, CA</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">YOUR happiness is a function of what you do with the opportunities in front of you.</title><link href="https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/09/23/title.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="YOUR happiness is a function of what you do with the opportunities in front of you." /><published>2023-09-23T22:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-09-23T22:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/09/23/title</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/09/23/title.html">&lt;p&gt;📍 San Francisco, CA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interstate 5 is a cathartic drive for those looking to escape the typical Californian scenery. Highway 1, on the other hand, is what a non-Californian native would expect when imagining the typical drive through California and, therefore, cannot be avoided in your California intrastate roadtrip plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would recommend trying Highway 1 at least once, but if you are anything like me, Interstate 5 is the way to go. While Highway 1 has tremendous views, Interstate 5 is a subtler experience. You are better able to focus on the drive itself and to think about whatever thoughts are on your mind. It is less entertaining but more prone to reflection, something I like to do while driving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Highway 1, however, you are given the option of stopping at small towns that offer a certain quaintness that is unmatched in Los Angeles or the San Francisco Bay Area. Personally, I did Topang, Ventura, Santa Barbara, Solvang, and Morro Bay. Of these, I would highly recommend Topang and Solvang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving from Los Angeles to Topang in the early hours of a Sunday morning felt isolating, enchanting, and rugged all at the same time. In order to arrive at Topanga, I had to exit through CA Highway 27, a misty, rocky, and winding road that led up to the small town with less than 10,000 inhabitants. I stopped for some coffee and breakfast, and admittedly watched football for two hours while working on this &lt;em&gt;tiympc&lt;/em&gt; blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/topanga-living-cafe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Topanga Living Cafe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was about 30 minutes from Solvang, a Danish-style town tucked away between the Santa Ynez and San Rafael mountains, I spontaneously stopped at Cachuma Lake Vista Point. I had no idea of my location at the time but impulsively paused my roadtrip plans by parking my car on this beautiful cliff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cachuma.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cachuma Lake Vista Point&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew that I needed to take in this view, and to share it with my father, who I FaceTimed immediately after I parked. He said that we will visit this spot together some day, and I really hope we do. He had a gigantic smile on his face. Although my father and I had trouble being honest about our feelings with each other when I was younger, I could tell that he was happy for me. I have never told him, but he is the man I aspire to be. If I can only have a fraction of his character, I know that my future children will be great people. I look forward to sharing all these specific thoughts the very next time I visit him. Without further adieu, I will definitely be back at this vista point, and I will definitely bring my father here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived at Solvang, I decided to use my camera to find anything worth photographing. I like studying different architecture and knew this Danish-style town was the place to go if I wanted to see something different than I’m used to in California. But, after a few minutes of walking through the towncenter, I abandoned my goal of a Solvang photoshoot. Instead, I decided to take it all in and to live in the moment, something I have recently gotten better at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 10 minutes of leaving town and resuming my roadtrip back to San Francisco, I had an interesting experience that I’d like to illustrate before wrapping up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m driving along a peaceful road. Symmetrical rows of tall, majestic western sycamore trees stand sentinel on either side. Their lush green leaves form a dense canopy overhead, filtering out the soft afternoon sunlight coming from the west into dappled patterns hitting my face and the road ahead.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am still driving at this point, so I don’t have too much time to observe my surroundings. However, I glance to my left and am immediatelly in awe of what I saw. My memory will never forget this image. Standing 20 meters perpendicular from my moving car was a gathering of chestnut horses, their heads bowed, delicately picking the wet, swampy grass underneath them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A black fence stood in the way between the horses and the road. Past the horses were the mountains of Santa Ynez, with a slight misty fog present. Sometimes - and I’m certain you’ve seen this happen before - angled sunlight hits the earth in such a way that the air around us comes alive and has a slight golden tinge to it, creating a magical atmosphere. Tiny, glistering particles, albeit invisible in the shadows, become revealed by the sun’s touch and seem to materialize in the sunlight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For a split second, I was convinved to pull off to the side of the road, cross the road camera in hand, and photograph this majestic scene. But I didn’t. I kept driving. And 20 minutes later, still with regret looming in my mind, I thought about turning back. I never did. A week after returning back to San Francisco, I still think about what a photo of this scene would look like. What could have been… But, we mustn’t linger on these feelings forever.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have to learn to let go and take advantage of the next great opportunity we’re given. I believe that a well-lived life consists of one where great opportunities are acted upon, whether in the context of business, love, friendship, community serivce, or whatever is important to you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Always, TIYMPC (do you know what this means yet?)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">📍 San Francisco, CA</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adventure IS the best way to learn.</title><link href="https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/09/16/title.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adventure IS the best way to learn." /><published>2023-09-16T22:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-09-16T22:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/09/16/title</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/09/16/title.html">&lt;p&gt;📍 Los Angeles, CA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every experience in life offers an oportunity to learn more about the world and to be a better human being. Although we all know this, adventures are especially prone to this phenomenon. Usually, adventures will not let us decide what we learn or how we grow. That’s the point of an adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot put into words what made me want to visit Los Angeles for the first time, especially alone. Maybe it was a combination of different factors, but regardless, I was on the road within one week of deciding that I needed to embark on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite driving alone and not needing to use my voice, Interstate 5 left me speechless. With mountains like gold and a sunset like neapolitan ice cream, I was left wondering when I would be able to make this drive again. California is a special part of this world, and I am lucky to be a part of this state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am writing from Motoring Coffee in Los Angeles. It is rare to find somewhere to sit down and sip an espresso, while just feet away from a Ferrari 348 Challenge and a dozen other rare vehicles. There is something special about combining two seemingly unconnected worlds, like coffee and cars: If anyone ever needs an idea for a brick-and-mortar business, consider a museum-themed coffee shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my seven-hour drive to Los Angeles, I must have seen around 200 18-wheelers. If California was its own country, she would boast the 5th largest GDP in the world, proving just how monumental this state is for the American economy. Personally, I have never seen so many trucks on the road, and I haven’t lived long enough in California to see what generates so much business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a young man from Pittsburgh, it’s difficult to comprehend what contributes to California’s prosperity. When I walk through the streets of San Francisco each day, I am faced with the harsh realities of today’s inequalities. What prosperity? There is no feeling more sad than seeing countless daughters, sons, mothers, fathers, sisters, brothers, and someone’s loved ones living on the streets of San Francisco. Homelessness and Pittsburgh is oxymoronic, or maybe I am privileged to be able to say that as I grew up in the quaint hills of Mount Lebanon, a community-centric township in Pittsburgh that is known for its “bubble.” That said, I had never seen the effects of homelessness until my 21st year on this earth, when I spent a summer in Manhattan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be tempting to be angry, disgusted, or spiteful towards the homeless population. However, I hope we can all acknowledge that sometimes we make poor choices in life. Other times, we’ve simply been dealt a bad hand. Remember to be kind to those on the streets. We don’t know their story. We can guess, but we don’t know. In other words, if you’re going to throw away that slice of pepperoni pizza that you weren’t able to finish, consider passing it off to someone who might need it. I can tell you from experience that the gratifying feeling you get from an act of kindness like this one doesn’t disappear with time. If you are a San Francisco local, consider volunteering &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sfmfoodbank.org/volunteer/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to give back to your community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have a moral obligation to try to pick up the man or woman next to us when they’ve stumbled. It doesn’t matter if you’re a Christian, a Muslim, an atheist, an agnostic, or if you believe in butterflies. We’re all human beings. We’ve all once fallen in love. We’ve all ridden a bicycle for the first time. We’ve all felt shame and grief. We’ve all laughed and cried. We’re human. You, me, and the person sleeping on the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its essence, this essay is not about homelessness. Yes, there are certain points I hope you takeaway about the subject, but I would like to instead close on three final thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is beauty in the world around us, even if it doesn’t make sense (e.g., coffee and cars). The hardest part is allowing yourself to be vulnerable and open to whatever conclusion you end up at. Once you become intentional about seeking beauty, you’ll find it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have a moral obligation to love those around you, regardless of where you’ve come from or what you believe in. Love is a complicated concept. I am still unsure about whether I truly understand its meaning, but I’ve learned that sometimes you have to think less and feel more. You’ll know when you’re doing it right, especially when you leave your heart open.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And, if you are in search of an adventure, take the drive through Interstate 5 - you won’t be sorry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, TIYMPC&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">📍 Los Angeles, CA</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TIME to write a blog.</title><link href="https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/08/27/title.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TIME to write a blog." /><published>2023-08-27T22:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-08-27T22:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/08/27/title</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tiympc.github.io/jekyll/update/2023/08/27/title.html">&lt;p&gt;📍 San Francisco, CA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;The only true wisdom is in knowing you know nothing.&lt;/em&gt;” - Socrates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been procastinating on this post: I’m unsure on what this blog is or what it will be. Bear with me as we witness the randomness of life and the ensuing knowledge that unfolds. Let’s join together in a patient quest to seek the secrets of the universe we live in. I hope that you find meaning in the works ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TIYMPC&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">📍 San Francisco, CA</summary></entry></feed>